vatsim.net 2013-05-22

# VATSIM - The International Online Flying Network: Privacy Policy

Upon your written request, VATSIM agrees to notify you of:

  1. Any personally identifiable information or third party personal identification that is collected from you through VATSIM's web site;
  2. The name of the organization collecting the information;
  3. How the information collected is to be used;
  4. With whom the information may be shared;
  5. What choices are available to you regarding collection, use and distribution of the information;
  6. The kind of security procedures that are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under VATSIM control;
  7. How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information.

If you feel that VATSIM is not following this privacy policy, you should contact the Vice President of Web Services at the email address posted at the VATSIM web site.

### Information Collection and Use

VATSIM is the sole owner of the information collected on this site. It will not sell, share or rent this information to others in ways different from what is disclosed in this Privacy Policy. VATSIM collects information from its users at several different points on its website.

### Registration

In order to use this website, you must first complete VATSIM'S registration form. During registration, you are required to give your contact information including name and an email address. This information is used to contact you about the services on our site for which you have expressed interest. Demographic information may be collected to comply with appropriate laws regarding children, to provide targeted services and to incorporate network security. Cookies as well as other means of personal unique identification will be used during the registration process. However, any personal data submitted will be kept strictly confidential and used only to identify you to the registration system.

### Cookies

VATSIM may use cookies on its site. A cookie is a piece of data stored on your hard drive which is used to track you through our site and for network security. Some of our affiliates may also use cookies on our site. However, VATSIM has no access to or control over these cookies.

### Log Files

VATSIM uses IP addresses to analyze trends, administer its site, track user's movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are linked to personally identifiable information for the purposes of network security. 

### Sharing of Certain Information

VATSIM may share aggregated demographic information with our partners and advertisers. This is not linked to any personal information that can identify any individual person. 

### Personal Statistical Information

In the normal course of connecting to the VATSIM network, certain personal statistical information will be collected. This information includes, but is not limited to, the time and duration of a member's connection, the callsign(s) used, flightplan(s) filed and other information necessary and useful for the maintenance of the network and your account. This personal information can be seen by other members and/or VATSIM affiliates and partners. In addition, this information may also be available to the general public via the internet. For further information regarding the availability of a member's personal statistical information, please see the VATSIM User Agreement.

### Links To Outside Websites

This web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that VATSIM is not responsible for the privacy practices or policies of such other sites. VATSIM encourages its members to be aware when they leave its website and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally  identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by VATSIM's web site.

### Required NOTAM Subscription

All VATSIM members are automatically subscribed to the email distribution of a NOTAM list. This list is used to distribute information of an urgent nature to all users of the VATSIM network. Subscription to this distribution list is automatic and mandatory for all users and is a condition of membership to VATSIM. This list is not used for any purpose other than official business.

### Surveys & Contests

From time-to-time, VATSIM and/or its affiliates and partners may request information from you for surveys or contests. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and you therefore have a choice whether or not to participate. Information requested may include contact information (such as name and shipping address) and demographic information (such as zip code or age). Contact information will only be used to notify the winners and award prizes. Survey information will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use and satisfaction of this site and/or the VATSIM network.

### Security

VATSIM takes every reasonable precaution to protect its members' information. When you submit sensitive information via the VATSIM website, your information is protected both online and offline. 

VATSIM will make all reasonable efforts to protect member information off-line. All member information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted. This information is password protected and only those people who need the information to perform a specific job (for example: Administrators, Conflict Resolution Staff, Supervisors and Divisional Directors) are granted access to personally identifiable information. If you have any questions about the security of the information you submit to VATSIM's website, you can send an email to the Vice President of Web Services at the email address posted at the VATSIM web site.

### Correction or Updating of Personal Information

If a user's personally identifiable information changes or needs correction, a  member should contact VATSIM's Membership Department at [http://www.vatsim.net/vatsim/members/memberservice/](http://www.vatsim.net/vatsim/members/memberservice/ "VATSIM Membership contact") for assistance in updating his or her account.

### Choice/Opt-out

Users who no longer wish to hold membership in VATSIM may optout at any time. Once your account has been closed, you will receive no further contact from VATSIM. To cancel your membership, please go to the following website: [http://www.vatsim.net/vatsim/members/memberservice/](http://www.vatsim.net/vatsim/members/memberservice/ "VATSIM Membership contact") and fill out the online form.

### Notification of Changes

If VATSIM decides to update or change its privacy policy, notice of such changes shall be posted on its website so members are always aware of what information is collected, how it may be used and/or disclosed. If at any point VATSIM decides to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, it will notify members by email so that they may decide whether to maintain or cancel their account.

### Minimum Age Requirement

VATSIM does not accept memberships from persons younger than the age of 13 under any circumstances and without exception. In addition, VATSIM does not allow any person under the age of 13 to join or post in its forum or to participate in the use of any online chat. VATSIM shall make every reasonable effort to prohibit persons under the age of 13 from participating in any of these venues. Any accounts created under false pretenses by persons under the age of 13 which are discovered and verified by VATSIM shall be immediately canceled.

### Contact

Questions concerning this privacy policy may be directed to the Vice President of Web Services at the email address posted at the VATSIM web site.
